Joseph Edward Davies Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part I: Newspaper Diary, 1941-1949 (Box I:114-146)
  - 1948 (Box I:136)
    - Oct.-Nov. (Box I:140)
    - Dec. (Box I:141)
  - 1949 (Box I:142)
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Mar.-Apr. (Box I:143)
    - May-June (Box I:144)
    - July-Aug. (Box I:145)
    - Sept.-Oct. (Box I:146)
- Part I: Miscellany, 1900-1956 (Box I:147-152)
  Articles, biographical notes, dinner lists, inventories, memoranda, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, and photostatic copies.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material or subject.
  - "Behind the Iron Curtain," Paul Schmidt, 1950 (Box I:147)
  - Biographical notes, 1952
  - Bullitt, William C., 1944
  - Canadian spy case, 1946
  - Catalog of books in dacha, 1951 (Box I:148)
  - Churchill, Sir Winston, speeches, 1941-1946
  - Dacha inventory, 1955 (Box I:149)
  - Dinner list, 1956
  - Eastman, Max, 1943
  - Ephemera, 1937-1941, undated
  - Hansard Parliamentary Debates, 1945 (Box I:150)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1941-1952
  - Printed matter
    - Balch, Thomas Willing, The Alaska Frontier, with related letter, 1900-1903
    - "The Bond Case of the Dominican Republic," 1934 (Box I:151)
    - Miscellany, 1943-1949, undated
  - Scrapbooks, 1943-1947 (Box I:152)
  - South American trip, 1950
- Part I: Addition, 1940-1941 (Box I:152)
  Correspondence, legal documents, blue prints, and printed matter relating to Fisherman's Island, Florida.
  - Fisherman's Island, Fla., legal matter, 1939-1941 (Box I:152)
- Part I: Oversize, 1899-1955 (Box I:OV 1)
  Campaign poster, photographs, and maps.
  Arranged according to the containers from which the items were removed.
  - Family and Personal File (Box I:OV 1)
    - Campaign material
      - Poster, Senate campaign, 1918 (Container I:1)
  - Speeches and Writings File
    - Books
      - “In the Days of Their Power and Glory”
        - Photographs, 1899-1955, undated (Container I:96)
      - Mission to Moscow
        - Background material
          - Maps, 1941-1943 (Container I:103)
- Part II: Family and Personal File, 1902-1958 (Box II:1-19)
  Appointment books, biographical and genealogical information, correspondence, estate records, financial records, household papers, medical records, social engagements, and university alumni material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Appointment books (Box II:1)
    - 1916, 1938-1939, 1945-1946, (4 folders)
    - 1947, (1 folder) (Box II:2)
    - 1948, (2 folders)
    - 1949-1950, (3 folders) (Box II:3)
    - 1951, (2 folders) (Box II:4)
    - 1952, (1 folder) (Box II:5)
    - 1953, (2 folders)
    - 1954, (2 folders) (Box II:6)
    - 1955, (1 folder) (Box II:7)
    - 1957
  - Biographical and genealogical information, 1919, 1936-1939, 1957, undated, (3 folders)
  - Correspondence (Box II:8)
    - 1912-1916, 1936-1951, (8 folders)
    - 1952-1958, undated, (7 folders) (Box II:9)
  - Estate records
    - Correspondence
      - 1911-1912
      - 1913
        - Jan.-Apr.
        - May-Dec., (2 folders) (Box II:10)
      - 1914-1916, 1949, (4 folders)
    - Court documents, 1906, 1912-1914
    - Financial records, 1907-1914
    - Miscellany, 1912-1914
    - Will, 1902 (Box II:11)
  - Financial records
    - Insurance, 1908-1916, 1937-1947, 1956, (2 folders)
    - Investments, 1912-1916, 1942-1957, (4 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1912-1916, 1945-1950, 1956
    - Taxes, 1913-1916, 1942-1949, (2 folders) (Box II:12)
  - Household papers
    - Apparel and jewelry, 1913-1916, 1940-1956
    - Art, antiques, and furniture, 1913-1916, 1928, 1937-1958, (7 folders)
    - Funeral arrangements, 1956-1958 (Box II:13)
    - Miscellany, 1912-1916, 1940-1958
    - Properties
      - American embassy, Brussels, Belgium, 1938
      - Minnesota, 1912-1916
      - North Dakota, 1916
      - Sea Cloud (ship)
        - Cruises and social events, 1935-1949, 1956, (3 folders)
        - License and registry, 1936, 1951
        - Maintenance and operations, 1936-1949
        - Military service
          - 1940-1942
          - 1943
            - Feb.-June
            - July-Dec. (Box II:14)
          - 1944-1951, (4 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1940-1950, 1956
        - Sale, 1936-1937, 1948-1949
      - Washington, D.C.
        - Le Roy Place, 1916-1917
        - Tregaron, 1948-1958 (Box II:15)
        - Twin Oaks, 1946-1947
      - Wisconsin
        - Ashland, 1912
        - Madison, 1912-1916, (2 folders)
        - Watertown, 1911-1916
    - Staff, 1941, 1951-1958
  - Medical records
    - Correspondence, 1912-1913, 1943-1958, (2 folders)
    - Diet, 1943, 1956-1957, (2 folders) (Box II:16)
  - Office records, 1912-1916, 1947-1957
  - Social engagements
    - Camp Topridge, Upper St. Regis, N.Y., 1949-1953
    - Christmas lists, 1948-1957
    - Clubs
      - Common Counsel Club, 1913-1914, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:17)
      - Miscellany, 1912-1916, 1946-1956, (2 folders)
    - Dinners and other events, 1913, 1937-1958, (4 folders)
    - Garden parties
      - 1946
      - 1956, May 1-2, (1 folder); (6 folders); (2 folders) (Box II:18, Box II:19)
      - 1957, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1957
    - Travel, 1913-1916, 1937-1957
  - University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wis., 1913-1916, 1938, 1948-1958, (2 folders)
- Part II: Correspondence, 1911-1958 (Box II:20-50)
  Incoming and copies of outgoing letters.
  - 1911 (Box II:20)
  - 1912
    - Jan.-July, (3 folders)
    - Aug.
      - 1-12, (4 folders)
      - 13-31, (5 folders) (Box II:21)
    - Sept.
      - 1-10, (3 folders)
      - 11-30, (3 folders) (Box II:22)
    - Oct.
      - 1-15, (4 folders)
      - 16-31, (5 folders) (Box II:23)
    - Nov.
      - 1-13, (4 folders)
      - 14-30, (4 folders) (Box II:24)
    - Dec., (5 folders)
  - 1913 (Box II:25)
    - Jan.-Feb., (6 folders)
    - Mar.
      - 1-22, (2 folders)
      - 24-31 (Box II:26)
    - Apr.-May, (8 folders)
    - June-July, (8 folders) (Box II:27)
    - Aug.-Sept., (6 folders) (Box II:28)
    - Oct.
      - 1-15, (2 folders)
      - 16-31, (2 folders) (Box II:29)
    - Nov., (5 folders)
    - Dec.
      - 1-5
      - 6-31, (4 folders) (Box II:30)
  - 1914-1915, (2 folders)
  - 1916
    - Jan., (4 folders)
    - Feb.-Mar., (7 folders) (Box II:31)
    - Apr.
      - 1-21, (2 folders)
      - 22-30 (Box II:32)
    - May-July, (9 folders)
    - Aug.-Nov., (9 folders) (Box II:33)
    - Dec., (3 folders) (Box II:34)
  - 1917-1921, 1927-1935, (3 folders)
  - 1936
    - Jan.-Oct.
    - Nov.
      - 3-24, (4 folders)
      - 25-30, (4 folders) (Box II:35)
    - Dec., (4 folders)
  - 1937
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Mar.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box II:36)
  - 1938
    - Jan.-May, (5 folders)
    - June-Dec., (7 folders) (Box II:37)
  - 1939
    - Jan.-Apr., (3 folders)
    - May-Dec., (3 folders) (Box II:38)
  - 1940, (4 folders)
  - 1941
    - Jan-Feb.
    - Mar.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box II:39)
  - 1942
    - Jan.-May, (5 folders)
    - June-Dec., (3 folders) (Box II:40)
  - 1943
    - Jan.-Aug., (6 folders)
    - Sept.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box II:41)
  - 1944, (8 folders)
  - 1945, (8 folders) (Box II:42)
  - 1946
    - Jan.-Feb., (2 folders)
    - Mar.-Dec., (7 folders) (Box II:43)
  - 1947
    - Jan.-Apr., (3 folders)
    - May-Dec., (5 folders) (Box II:44)
  - 1948, (3 folders)
  - 1949-1951, (10 folders) (Box II:45)
  - 1952-1953, (10 folders) (Box II:46)
  - 1954-1955, (7 folders) (Box II:47)
  - 1956
    - Jan.-Feb., (2 folders)
    - Mar.-Sept., (8 folders) (Box II:48)
    - Oct.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box II:49)
  - 1957
    - Jan.-July, (6 folders)
    - Aug.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box II:50)
  - 1958, undated, (4 folders)
- Part II: Subject File, 1912-1956 (Box II:51-52)
  Chiefly printed matter on topics relevant to Davies's career, such as Belgium, election campaigns, and universal military training.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Belgium, 1938-1939, (2 folders) (Box II:51)
  - Economic and foreign relations, 1938-1939
  - Election campaigns, 1912, 1918 See also Oversize, (2 folders)
  - Fruehauf Trailer Co., 1955-1956
  - Miscellany, undated
  - Post-World War II, 1943-1945
  - Universal military training, 1946-1947, (5 folders) (Box II:52)
- Part II: Speeches and Writings File, 1913-1958 (Box II:53-63)
  Correspondence, notes, research material, and galleys relating to Davies's articles, books, and speeches.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Articles, 1941-1945, 1952, (6 folders) (Box II:53)
  - Books
    - “In the Days of Their Power and Glory”
      - Background information, 1938, 1953-1955
      - Drafts
        - 1952-1956
        - 1957, (2 folders) (Box II:54)
      - Miscellany, 1952-1954
      - Notes, 1953-1957
      - Proofs, 1956 See also Oversize, (2 folders)
    - “Letters and Diary” (Box II:55)
      - Background information, 1917, 1939-1958
      - Diary entries
        - 1937-1942, (5 folders)
        - 1943
          - Jan.-Apr., (2 folders)
          - May-Nov., (2 folders) (Box II:56)
        - 1944-1945, (6 folders)
        - 1946-1956, (4 folders) (Box II:57)
      - Drafts
        - Miscellaneous pages, 1950-1956, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:58)
        - Set I, undated
        - Set II, 1950-1954, (3 folders)
      - Forward, preface, and outlines, 1945-1954
      - Notes, 1941-1957, (3 folders) (Box II:59)
    - Mission to Moscow, 1942-1947, (2 folders)
    - “Missions for Peace” (Box II:60)
      - Background information and notes, 1938-1950
      - Drafts, 1948-1950
    - “The Russians; the Land, the People, and Why They Fight,” 1943
  - Film, Mission to Moscow
    - Contracts, 1942-1943
    - Correspondence, 1942-1950, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1941, 1956
    - Publicity and reviews, 1943, (2 folders)
    - Royalty statements, 1944-1948
  - Forewords and introductions, 1942-1944 (Box II:61)
  - Interviews, 1942-1944
  - Miscellany
    - Correspondence, 1942-1950, 1960
    - Research material, undated
    - Work plans, 1953-1954
    - Writings by others, 1914, 1931-1957, (3 folders)
  - Speeches and statements
    - 1913-1917, 1937-1940, (2 folders)
    - 1941-1945, (9 folders) (Box II:62)
    - 1946-1955, undated, (4 folders) (Box II:63)
- Part II: Press File, 1913-1957 (Box II:63-68)
  Bulletins, newsletters, newspaper clippings, newspaper diary, press releases, and radio broadcasts.
  - Bulletins and newsletters (Box II:63)
    - American Russian Institute, 1943-1944
    - British Information Services Notes, 1946-1947, (3 folders)
    - Changing World, 1945-1947 (Box II:64)
    - Daily Bulletin, 1938-1939, (5 folders)
    - Dominican Republic, 1946-1953, (3 folders)
    - Foreign Report
      - 1946
      - 1947-1948, (3 folders) (Box II:65)
    - Miscellany, 1947-1950, 1956-1957
    - News From Germany, 1940
  - Newspaper clippings, 1913-1918, 1937-1957, (7 folders)
  - Newspaper diary (Box II:66)
    - 1938-1946, (6 folders)
    - 1947
      - Jan.-Sept., (3 folders)
      - Oct.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box II:67)
    - 1948, (5 folders)
    - 1949
      - Jan.-Aug.
      - Sept.-Oct. (Box II:68)
  - Press releases, 1937-1948, 1957, (2 folders)
  - Radio broadcasts, 1943
- Part II: Miscellany, 1893-1957 (Box II:68-72)
  Notes, photographs, printed matter, and scrapbooks.
  - Certificate of commissioner of conciliation, 1926 (Box II:68)
  - Notes, 1930-1940
  - Photographs, 1938, 1950, 1956
  - Printed matter
    - 1893, 1910-1916, 1937-1939, (4 folders)
    - 1940-1957, undated, (6 folders) (Box II:69)
  - Scrapbooks (Box II:70)
    - American embassy, Bruxelles, Belgium, 1938
    - Belgium, compiled by Rahel Walker, 1938-1939 See Oversize
    - Cardiff, Wales, 1937
    - Davies, Joseph Edward, 1910-1917 (Box II:71)
    - Davies family, 1936-1942, (3 folders); (7 folders) (Box II:72)
- Part II: Oversize, 1912-1956 (Box II:OV 1-OV 3)
  Book galley, campaign posters, and scrapbook.
  Arranged according to the series and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Subject File (Box II:OV 1)
    - Election campaigns
      - Posters, 1912 (Container II:51)
  - Speeches and Writings File (Box II:OV 2)
    - Books
      - “In the Days of Their Power and Glory”
        - Proofs, 1956 (Container II:54)
  - Miscellany (Box II:OV 3)
    - Scrapbooks
      - Belgium, compiled by Rahel Walker, 1938-1939 (Container II:70)
        - Part I
        - Part II (Box II:OV 4)